REILLY ANDERSON FULL-STACK WFR DEVELOPER

Summary

Full-stack web developer with experience in JavaScript and Python. Self-starter who works well in teams under tight deadlines. Creates efficient code and is well versed in best git collaboration practices. Critical thinker with advanced analytical skills who tackles challenges creatively and picks up new subject areas rapidly.

Projects

PolifiCal Jan 2018 to Current

Designed and implemented a MERN stack calendar app that allows users to add calendars, join group calendars, control events, and introduces a dynamic UI for easy visibility of events in all views. (currently in development). Technologies: Node.js, Mongodb, Mongoose, React, RESTful APIs, JavaScript(ES6), HTML, CSS

Gourmet Group Jan 2018 to Jan 2018

Designed and implemented a recipe web app that allows users to search for existing recipes (using a recipe API), save recipes to their wishlist, upload photos of what they've made, and add their own personal recipes. Technologies: Node.js, EJS, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, RESTful API, Materialize

Dec 2017 to Dec 2017

Developed a front-end UNO game that allows for up to twelve players. Technologies: JavaScript, jQuery, Boostrap, CSS, HTML

Employment

Scripps College Academy

Program Assistant

Claremont. CA Sep 2013 to May 2017

Programming and Data Analysis responsibilities included maintaining the web portal for students, with an emphasis on UI and accessibility, creating analytics for scholar performance improvement on ACT tests, and using LaTeX to write documents for large-scale information distribution.

Kineta, Inc.

Research Assistant

Seattle, WA

Summer Research Intern Jun 2015 to Aug 2015

Kineta is a biotechnology company that develops immunotherapies and investigates drug advancement in oncology and virology.

Conducted laboratory research on viruses, primarily Hepatitis C, Dengue Fever, and Influenza, for the purpose of finding, creating, and testing combative, broad-spectrum anti-viral compounds for potential as medications.

Coordinated weekly experiments on potential compounds, experiment/data analysis using a mix of R and Microsoft Excel, daily cell splitting and laboratory maintenance.

WM Keck Science Inst. - Schmitz Laboratory

Claremont. CA Sep 2014 to Dec 2015

Assisted in the collection, dissection, preservation, and analysis of mammal eye specimens, for the purpose of mapping the layout of ganglion cells in different species' retinas in order to track evolutionary trends and differences between land and water species.

Used R and R Studio in the analysis of retinal results and assisted in the creation of the R retinal topography map package.

Contact

reillyjanderson@gmail.com

www.reillyanderson.com

Seattle, WA

in reilly-anderson/

C RAnderso0325

Education

General Assembly

Web Development Immersive 2018

Full-stack Web Development Program with 700+ hours in class and creating deliverables. Highly focused on the implementation of the MERN stack with exposure to ReactJS, Python, and Diango. Agile work environments and Git workflows utilized in assignments and project sprints.

Scripps College

BA International and Intercultural Studies 2017

In addition, also successfully completed a PreMedical Track

Universidad de Buenos Aires y Instituto Desarrollo Económico y Social

2016

Winter quarter spent studying art, memory, and social transformation in Buenos Aires and Córdoba, Argentina

Skills

CODING JavaScript, HTML, CSS,

> Node.is, Diango, Python, LaTeX, React.js, SQL, MongoDB, PostGres, jQuery, RESTful APIs, R,

R Studio

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Proficient in Spanish, Microsoft Word. Microsoft Excel,

Microsoft PowerPoint, Microsoft Outlook